DAN KLEIN: The story is actually
reversed for the case of values.
So for value ordering, what we do is
we have a variable that we picked.
So for example, here on the Australia
case, we decided that for whatever
reason we're assigning
to this variable.
And the question is, what
should we assign it?
And our choice here, we can assign it
to red, we can assign it to blue.
Well, which one should we do?
It's kind of hard to tell just
in terms of the value itself.
But if we imagine assigning red and we
think about the consequences, and we
imagine assigning blue and think about
the consequences, what you'll discover
is assigning blue is kind of bad news,
because this variable here becomes
much more constrained.
In particular, it becomes
over-constrained and we would fail.
OK, so it's better to assign red here.
And the general idea here is, given a
choice of variable, we should pick the
value that is least constraining
to try first.
That is, the value that rules out the
fewest other values in remaining
variables elsewhere.
Now of course, computing this may take
some time, so we might have to assign
tentatively each one of these values,
do our filtering, either forward
checking or arc consistency, and
see how many things vanished.
That's expensive.
But it helps us be smart about
what value to take next.
Now here, of course, we kind of
went in the other direction.
We went the easy way and the difference
is, when you're picking a
variable, you have to do them all.
You want to do the hard ones first.
When you're picking a value, you
don't have to do them all.
You only have to do the ones
that are going to work.
So you might as well try the things
that are likely to work.
If you combine these ordering ideas, now
suddenly you can do 1,000 queens,
so much bigger problems.